A quest to save her world.
Raya and the Last Dragon is a animation, family,
fantasy film directed by Don Hall.
Long ago, in the fantasy world of Kumandra, humans
and dragons lived together in harmony.
But when an evil force threatened the land, the dragons
sacrificed themselves to save humanity.
Now, 500 years later, that same evil has returned and it’s up to a lone warrior, Raya, to track
down the legendary last dragon to restore the fractured land and its divided people.
Raya (voice), played by Kelly Marie Tran.
Sisu (voice), played by Awkwafina.
Namaari (voice), played by Gemma Chan.
Tuk Tuk (voice), played by Alan Tudyk.
Boun (voice), played by Izaac Wang.
Tong (voice), played by Benedict Wong.
Raya and the Last Dragon ( RYE-ə) is a 2021 American animated fantasy
action film produced by Walt Disney Animation Studios.
It was directed by Don Hall and Carlos López Estrada, and written by Qui Nguyen and Adele Lim, and stars the
voices of Kelly Marie Tran, Awkwafina, Izaac Wang, Gemma Chan, Daniel Dae Kim, and Benedict Wong.
The film's plot follows the warrior princess Raya as she seeks the fabled last dragon to save
her father and the land of Kumandra from evil spirits that are known as Druun.
Development of the project began in October 2018, and it was officially
announced in August 2019, and the title and voice cast were revealed.
During production, Disney replaced several cast and crew members, including the initially announced lead
actor Cassie Steele, who was replaced with Tran to conform with changes in character and plot.
The film is inspired by traditional Southeast Asian cultures.
During design and animation, the filmmakers focused on diverse environments and
characters while maintaining authentic cultural representation.
James Newton Howard composed the film's score.
Raya and the Last Dragon was released in theaters in the United States on March 5, 2021, and
simultaneously on the streaming platform Disney+ for customers with Premier Access.
The film was twice delayed from its November 2020
release date due to the COVID-19 pandemic.
The film became the third-most-streamed film of 2021
and grossed $130.4 million worldwide.
The film received positive reviews from critics and was nominated for several
accolades, including an Academy Award nomination for Best Animated Feature.
The film explores themes of kung fu, sword, warrior
woman, female protagonist, dragon.